# Rodrigo Leles

# Fullstack Digital Designer

rodrigoleles.com
dribbble.com/rodrigoleles
instagram.com/rodrigo\_leles

contato@rodrigoleles.com +55 11 996 209 728

Multi-disciplinary digital designer based in São Paulo, Brazil. I have been building digital products and brands with focus on crafting neat user experiences for +10 years. Currently working as a freelancer with various agencies, startups, companies and people all over the world.

#### **Experience**

Senior Product Designer at IFTTT • Mar 2021 - Jul 2024

IFTTT is a leading internet connectivity platform providing integration and connectivity solutions to the world's most innovative brands, helping 22 million people discover and create useful integrations. My work there was find balance between wath their users wanted and what they actually needed. That was possible through research and UI experiences and tests, that had real positive impact on monthly revenue and other business goals.

Head of Design at Cooklist • Aug 2018 - Mar 2020

Cooklist has an amazing mission: Make people eat intelligently. My role was not only define the UX vision and strategy but create the end-to-end customer experience and UI at both the macro and micro interaction level. We talked to our users to gather data about our assumptions and uncover the best solutions, identified and measured critical KPIs, metrics, and business outcomes. The product was one of the 2018's Techstars Acceleration program winners.

UX Lead at 99 • Sep 2017 - Aug 2018

99 is the the largest brazilian mobile application of urban mobility, one of the largest startup in Latin America and the first Brazillian unicorn. I joined the safety squad, helping the team to understand what makes a ride safe for passengers and drivers, and how can we make better design solutions there was not only funny, quick and affordable, but safer too.

UX Designer at Anheuser-Busch InBev • Jul 2015 - Aug 2017

As part of Anheuser-Busch InBev Disrupt Growth Office I was in charge of brand guidelines, UI design and shared digital assets for the global courier solution, assuring that the UX solutions based on Brazil, Mexico, Argentina and Dominican Republic were following best practices and design patterns. Part of this work was to create an A/B testing center of excellence, plan the iterations of the Brazilian platform and manage designers spread across different timezones.

Digital Art Director at Artplan • Oct 2014 - Jul 2015

Artplan is the 19th largest ad agency in Brazil and the largest with 100% national capital. With offices in São Paulo, Rio de Janeiro and Brasilia. As the Senior Art Director my job consisted in creating and developing ideas in a multiplatform format of integrated campaigns. Participate in projects for clients as Amil, Amanco, Estácio, Itaipava, Etna, Niely, Melitta, Caixa, Rock in Rio, among others.

## Education

Interview Workshop: Get the Most out of Your Interviewees • 2018 Ivan Mizansuk (online)

Intensive Art Direction • 2017

Escola CUCA

Design, Aesthetics and Art Direction  $\, \cdot \,$  2016

Saulo Milleti

Digital Design Bachelor. • 2007 - 2010

Anhembi Morumbi University

## Certifications

The 10k Website Process • 2020 Flux Academy (Teachable)

The Webflow Masterclass • 2019 Flux Academy (Teachable)

UX Design On Demand • 2016 General Assembly

Lean Six Sigma White Belt • 2016 Anheuser-Busch InBev